願う…
ではなく…
でもこれが…
形はいびつだ
黒光りする泥団子
握りしめた分だけ硬くなる
七色に輝く びいどろ…
自分自身の指の型（かたち）…
それは 力を込めると砕けてしまう
いつか 美しい宝石になる為じゃなく
世界で一番美しい泥団子になる為の…
ジーザスお向かいさんなの
聞いてやばいの
目覚めのキッスはまどろむあなたに
あやかしリップなお姫様
出会いの切符は夢見るあなたに
まやかしVIPなエア・フォース
時間がないの いま何時？
授業開始の５分前
ヴィーナスお隣さんなの どうして？
知らない間に
急いでないの いま大事
あなたに出会う５分前
To wish
大胆あいつの攻撃
バイバイ気づいてない振り
To wish...
大胆あいつの衝撃 まさに生き地獄
寝起きのキックは挨拶代わりに
生足いっつも傷だらけ
Hold a wish in your hands, and it will
not shatter under the pressure.
It is not a fragile, shimmering glass ball.
手持ちのチップをあの子に賭けたら
まばたきみっつでノック・ダウン
No. Instead...
A wish hardens and takes
shape as you hold it tight.
嫌いじゃないの 嫌なだけ
予測出来ないこの気持ち
It is a dark and glossy lump of clay.
期待しないで 暇なだけ
あなたと消える５分間
Its shape may not be perfect.
But still...
It retains the contours of our hands and fingers.
ヴィーナスあの子はいつでもそうなの？
いまなら間に合う
Its purpose is not to transform into a perfect gem,
ジーザス引き返せないの 早く気付いて
but rather to become the most
beautiful lump of clay imaginable.
Chapter 77: "Fire Drill"
A blue sky stretches itself across the window.
窓の外は抜けるような青空…
Sunbathing in the summer breeze
is incredibly pleasant.
初夏の風を体に受けながらの
日向ぼっこは心地いい…
Ahh, truly this is the smell of summer.
はあー 夏の匂いがするなぁ…
Or... the smell of something burning?
ん？ なんか焦げ臭い？
あー まずこれは訓練
Attention please! This is a drill!
This is a fire drill!
防災訓練である
Oh, is that all?
ああ なんだ どっかで防災訓練
So it's just...
ウッホッ
a fire drill.
やってらあ
ウフッ ウハッ！
Fire alarm! Fire alarm!
えー 火災発生！ 火災発生！
There's a major fire by the river!
河川敷で火災発生！
This is only a drill.
という想定である
There really is a fire!
って 本当に火つけちゃうのかよ！
What are you doing? You're crazy incarnate!
何やってんだ！ この歩く非常事態！
Hey Rec, you're the first one—
やあリク 早いなあ 一番乗りだ
This is no fire drill! It's
想定っつーより放火！
This is arson! You're an arsonist!
これ 放火ですよっ！
Not to worry.
大丈夫だ
I've cleared the surrounding brush.
周りの草は刈ってある
Oh... so the fire won't spread, right?
おお 拡がらないようになってるんだ…
はっはっは 慌て過ぎだぜリクルート！
Stop freaking out, Recruit.
なっ なんだ？ いるのかよ村長！
Huh? Where are you, Chief?
Well, at least you reacted quickly to the fire.
まあ 火を見て走って来たのは
感心だけどよ…
But you have to stay cool,
especially at times like this.
こういう時こそ
クールでいねえとダメだぜ…
Sure, fire can be dangerous.
確かに火は怖えもんだが…
But we can also control it
and make it work for us.
俺達は火を支配することも
できるんだからな…
Then, why don't you climb down from there before you say that?
じゃあ まずそこから
降りてきたらどうですか？
Jeez. Sister, you shouldn't coddle him like that!
つーか シスターもダメですよ
甘やかしちゃ！
This is hardly coddl
-これくらい 別に甘やかすに入らん
-あー なんか小腹減ったなあ
Oh man, I'm really hungry.
ハグッ！ お シスター済まねえな ウグ
Thanks, Sister.
うん シスターのクッキーは
最高だなあ うぐ
Your cookies are the best.
So are you some kind of
mama bird or something?
シスターは母鳥か何かですか？
This is just too weird! I know you can
use food to tame animals, but
今のは本当におかしいですよ！
シスターに餌付けの癖があるのは
知ってますが
Yes, well... if you tried to do the same
thing, I'd turn you into swiss cheese.
まあ 貴様が同じことをしたら
すまんが 蜂の巣にせざるを得ない
Isn't that a little extreme?!
それも思い切り過ぎじゃ
ありませんかあ！
Actually, I'm in the Chief's debt.
村長には恩がある
Ahh, I can feel myself drying out.
あー 沸点近いかも…
お 済まねえなあ シスター
Thanks, Sister.
Check it out! This water has collagen in it,
so my head-plate will feel fresh and moisturized.
しかもこれ
“コーラゲン入りオイシイ水”じゃね？
皿もプルプル 気が利くなあ
Don't mention it.
いえ これぐらい
Hey, wai—
いやっ ちょ…
You're being way too nice! It's disconcerting!
気が利き過ぎだし いらん世話だよっ！
They say a kappa will become weak
as a baby if its head-plate dries out.
河童は皿の水を失うと
赤子のように非力になると言います…
Chapter 78: "Teamwork"
Are we too close to the fire?
Shall we move farther away?
火に近すぎますか？
離れましょうか？
It's fine, it's fine.
いって いってえ
I've been wondering for a while,
even before today...
それにしても
前から気になってはいたけど…
Just let me know if you need anything.
では 何かありましたら
'Kay!
おうっ
Why is Sister always so eager to please the
Chief? I doubt Sister's intimidated by him.
なんでシスターは
村長にだけ敬語なんだ？
大して強そうでもないし
ヘラヘラしてるし…
I don't see any reason why he should
respect the Chief so much.
シスターが敬語使うような要素なんて…
Anyway, it's super hot out here.
しかし熱いなあ…
Aw man, you're the first one here?
あ～ なんだ テメエが１番かよ
あっ 星！
Hoshi!
Cripes, another wildfire this year, huh?
うわ～ しかし今年もスゲーなあ…
You should never take fire lightly.
火ってのは迫力が…
Oh my god! You're wilting!
おいっお前！ 柔らかくなってるぞ！
Ahh! Ohcrapohcrapohcrapohcrap!
ああ！ やべ やべやべ…
まー リクじゃない
Hey, it's Rec.
You sure got here fast.
お～ 早いんだな
So everyone does come running... sort of.
本当にみんな集まるんですねえ
Sure, it's a yearly event.
毎年恒例だからな
Really? So... what do we do now?
そうなんですか？
けど これからいったい何を？
The highlight of every fire drill,
of course. The fire brigade!
そりゃあ もちろん
防災訓練のハイライトと言えば
バケツリレーだ
We put the fire out by handing
off a bucket filled with water.
荒川の水が入ったバケツを
バトンの要領で渡していき 消火する
Teamwork is the key to victory!
まさにチームワークが鍵となる
消火方法よ！
That's gonna be impossible
for all you solo artists!
ワンマンプレイヤーばかりの橋の下で
無茶言うな！
All right, let's do it!
さあ 始めよう！
Woo! I wanna be in front!
わーい！ 僕一番前がいい！
僕が前だ～い！
No, me!
Hey, be careful! Kids shouldn't
go anywhere near the fire!
おい 危ないぞ 子供は後ろの方にいろよ
Yup. Grown men should be
closest to the fire, right?
先頭は成人男子がいいんじゃねーかあ？
Right. Grown men. Preferably ones who aren't
wearing potentially flammable masks.
ですね 成人男子で しかも
マスクを被っていない俺かシロさんか
シスターでしょうねえ
Which leaves me, Whitey, or Sister.
Now just hold on. Why didn't you include me?
ちょ 待てよ なんで俺入ってねーの？
Just because I'm a spirit? Is that it?
妖怪はハブ？ そいうこと？
No. But it would be a real shame
if you caught on fire.
いや 別に…
万が一着火したら大変でしょ？
俺 ゴムの焼ける匂い 嫌いだし…
I don't like the smell of burning rubber, you see.
Gift of immortality
Fool! If I catch fire, all you'll smell
is my legendary aroma!
Gift of immortality
ばかやろう！
俺が焼けたら幻の珍味だぞ！
Gift of immortality
You should stop trying so hard.
無理しなくて いいですって…
チィッ
You've cast the gauntlet.
Now I really can't back down!
そうまで言われて
黙ってられっかってんだ！
I'll be at the very front. Everyone, line up!
先頭は俺がやるぜっ！
よし みんな！ 一直線に並べー！
Okay!
は～い！
Now, follow my lead!
俺のかけ声に合わせてくれよなっ！
Yeeaaah!
Dosukoi! Dosukoi!
ドスコイ
ドスコイ ドスコイ
Wow.
へえー かけ声はともかく…
That weird chant aside,
everyone seems to be in sync.
-みんな 結構息合うんだなあ
-ドスコイ　ドスコイ
ドスコイ
No, it might actually be because of his chanting.
-いや むしろ村長のかけ声のお陰か？
-ドスコイ　ドスコイ
ドスコイ　ドスコイ
ドスコイ
ドスコイ！
He's... a surprisingly good leader.
こいつ… 案外本当に頼りに…
Here we go!
よし来たーっ！
ドスコーイ！
Ow! Hot hot hot!
あちゃっ！ あちゃっ！ あちちっ！
I'm drying out!
皿っ… 皿が乾く！
Just go get in back!
だったら大人しく後ろにいろよっ！
The Chief is such a brave soul!
困難に立ち向かう村長って素敵！
Go, my hero!
よっ男気！
You can do it, Chief!
頑張って！ 村長～！
The next one's coming right up!
すぐに次まわすねーっ！
He certainly is well-regarded.
慕われては いるみたいです…
Chapter 79: "The Chief Under the Bridge"
What are you doing?
何やってんだーっ！
We're all working hard here!
せっかく運んだのにっ！
I know I am!
いや～
一仕事
Sister, you can't let him act like this!
シスターも甘やかさないで下さい！
Whew, time for a break.
ちょっと休むべ…
You—
こいつ…
Here's a pillow.
枕を…
I mean, seriously! What's with
this crazy personal attention?
本当 待って下さい
なんなんですか？ その尽くし方
You said you owed him, but what kind of favor
could he possibly have done for you?
さっき恩とか言ってましたけど…
それだけで そこまでなりますか？
It's more than just some favor.
まあ 恩だけではないな…
So what, he's blackmailing you?
やはり何か脅されて
ううわあっ！ 大変だあ！
Oh no!
The wind blew the fire over here!
風で飛び火しちゃったよー！
お 落ち着けえ！
C-Calm down! Just follow the "three don'ts"!
“おはし”！ “おはし”の約束だあ！
How's it go? Don't stop, don't drop, don't roll?
“お”れの “は”なしは “し”んどい
だっけ？
No! The three don'ts apply strictly
to evacuation procedures!
違うし！
“おはし”は避難の時の約束だ！
Specifically, it's "don't push, don't
run, and don't shout", correct?
Don't push
うん 正しくは “おさない“ “はしらない”
“しゃべらない” だねえ
Don't run
Don't shout
I knew we shouldn't have let
Kappa-man handle it to begin wi—
やっぱり
河童になんて任せず はじめから…
Chief, what are you—
村長 何を？
Just let him do his thing.
村長に任せておけ
How can I? He's just some costumed fr—
任せられませんよ！ あんな着ぐるみ…
It's more than just some favor.
恩だけで言っている訳じゃない
He can be trusted completely.
He's worth taking care of.
村長は尊敬できる
尽くすだけの価値のある男だよ
Also...
それに…
He loves this place more than anyone else.
誰よりも この橋の下を愛している
けど バケツも持たずに…
He doesn't even have a bucket.
I have to put everything I've
got into this one attack!
この攻撃に… 俺の全てを賭ける！
Chief!
村長！
Here we go! The Spirit Special!
いくぜ！ 妖怪秘術！
Kappattack!
河童の最後っ屁！
Chief!
村長！
Good job, Chief!
グッジョブ 村長！
Nice spray, Chief!
ナイス水！ 村長ー！
He used the water on his head-plate!
皿の水を投げ出すとは！
He's worthless!
使えねえしっ！ やっぱ騙されてるよっ！
Wake up, sheeple!
They're completely blind
Hip hip hooray! Hip hip hooray!
村長に対してみんな 盲目過ぎです
when it comes to the Chief.
Chapter 80: "Awakening"
Kamakura
Yes, that's correct. The large area right
in the center of the Arakawa River.
ええ そうです
Yokohama
Tokyo
Kawasaki
荒川中流付近の広い河川敷です
Arakawa
We'll take care of everything on our end.
工事もわが社に一任して下されば…
Sure. Goodbye.
ええ ではまた
Mr. Ichinomiya, I have the
weekly report on your son.
市ノ宮様…
行様の ここ１週間の報告です
Excellent.
ご苦労
Look at his idiotic face.
ずいぶん間抜けな顔になったものだ…
Freedom.
自由も… 権利も… 居場所も…
Rights.
Land.
They all belong to the people
with the most money.
全て金を多く積んだ人間のものだ！
They simply aren't things a man
of your caliber has earned.
お前程度の力で
手に入るものではないことを
It's time you realized that.
教えてやる
Sparkling green land laid out beneath
busy-looking men in colorless gray suits.
緑の眩しい河川敷に
忙しく動き回る灰色のスーツの男達
It was truly an odd sight to behold.
それは非常に浮いて見えた…
Who are those guys?
なんだ あの人達…
All right, let's move to the next site.
よーし 次のポイントに移動！
Excuse me... what's going on here?
あ あの～ 何してるんです？
あん？ 地盤の調査だよ
We're surveying the land.
For research or something?
研究か何かですか？
No, for the upcoming construction.
いやあ 工事の前調査さ
We're reclaiming all the land around here.
この辺きちんと整備してねえ
公園みたいにするんだって
It'll become a kind of park area.
Have you seen the area downstream?
With the tennis courts and such?
下流の方行ったことない？
テニスコートとかあるでしょ？
えっ な… なんで急にそんなこと…
Wh-Why now, all of a sudden?
Has this already been decided?
決定なんですか？
That I don't know. What I do know is our
president is spearheading this project himself.
さあねえ…
その辺は僕らも知らないけど…
このプロジェクト うちの社長が
直接持ち掛けたみたいだから
Huh? The president of...
いったいどこの？
Ichinomiya Corporation
Ichi
The Ichinomiya Group. I'm sure you've
heard the name before, yes?
Ichinomiya Corporation
市ノ宮グループ
君も名前くらいは知ってるでしょう？
W-W—
We have a serious problem!
大変ですーっ！
Nuclear—
核か？
No, nothing nuclear.
いえ 核では…
Checkmate.
王手
Aww man, you suck.
あー！ なんだよ ひでーなあ
Shall I lose next time?
じゃあ ２局目は負けましょうか
Sister, there's more to fear in the
world than just nuclear war!
シスター！ 世の中には核以外にも
怖いものはあるんですよお！
What's with all the yelling?
なんだよ 騒々しいな～
Listen, Chief! You see...
村長！ じ… 実は…
So your dad's trying to buy up the area?
親父さんがこの橋の下を
買おうとしてる？
Yes.
はい…
Gotta say, this seems like overkill.
豪快なパパさんだなあ
Is he the kind of guy who lets stress
drag him into impulse buys like this?
何？ ストレスで
衝動買いとかしちゃう人？
Well, no, it's just that for some reason
いや… 買うっていうか…
he's offered to develop the area
at a ridiculous discount.
すごい安値で
開発を申し出たらしいんです…
He might have found out I'm living down here.
もしかしたら 俺がここにいるのが
バレたのかも…
I don't know what he's thinking,
何考えてるか分かりませんが…
but he's the kind of guy who
always gets what he wants.
父さんは やると決めたことは
必ず実現します！
You seem to be extremely afraid of your father.
貴様は ずいぶんと父親が怖いようだな…
Damn right I am! If you knew what kind
of person he is, you would be too!
怖いですよ！
シスターだって あの人を知れば…
Rec, let me read to you some
words from scripture:
リクよ… 久しぶりに聖書でも
読んでやろう
"Love your enemies."
汝の敵を愛せよ
That's not very helpful!
そういうことじゃ…
Buddha says something similar:
仏陀も言っているぞ
That's not even your religion, is it?
"No one can survive an attack aimed here."
何人（なんぴと）も…
Here
ここを狙えば一発だい
そう思えば どんな人にも
優しくなれるだろう？
Remember that, and you'll want
to be nice to everyone you meet.
Mmm, I see.
なるほどなあ～…
So is that all you see when you look at people?!
あんた いつも！
そんなこと考えて人の顔見ているのか！
State
of
E
M
R
gency
Chapter 81: "State of Emergency"
Since Rec's here, should we
break out a deck of cards?
じゃあ リクも来たことだし
トランプにするかあ？
Giving up already?
逃げましたね
H—
How can you be so calm?
Don't you see what's happening here?!
何をのんきな！
事態が分かってるんですか？
There's a very real possibility we won't be able
to stay down here once the construction starts!
本格的な整備が始まったら
ここには住んでいられないかも
知れないんですよお！
My father's trying to force us all to leave.
父さんは
俺達を丸ごと追い出す気かも…
You can't win against someone like him.
戦って勝てる相手じゃないし…
He'll have the government and
media on his side for sure!
警察やマスコミだって
父さんの味方ですよ！
うーん 確かにマスコミはなあ…
Hmm, the media would be bad news.
あ～ かぱちゃ～ん！
Cute!
Kyaah!
Ahh, it's Kappa-chan!
So cute!
It's Kappa-chan!
Look at him!
I really don't wanna become some
kind of overnight celebrity.
荒川の“かぱちゃん”とか いきなり
アイドル状態は はっ ちょっとなぁ…
It's Kappa-chan!
Look at him!
Cute!
Kyaah!
It's Kappa-chan!
Look at him!
Cute!
Kyaah!
It's Kappa-chan!
Look at him!
Cute!
Kyaah!
Enough of your fantasies!
何甘い夢を見ているんですかあ！
We're breaking the law just by being down here.
だいたい 俺達の存在は
法に触れてるんですよ
If the police get involved, I highly doubt
they'll let us off with a warning.
もし警察なんて呼ばれたら
厳重注意で済むかどうか…
Really?
そうなのか？
Yes, really!
そうですよ！
I see.
そうか
I mean, I don't think they'd
actually arrest us, but—
まあ 逮捕はないかも知れませんが
ん？ なんだ？
What?
Kidnapping
What is it?
どうした？
Possession of firearm
Noise violations
Illegal immigration
There's a 100% chance this
guy's going away for good!
100％捕まる人いたー！
Argh! You have to go back to
England, right this second!
うおおー！ あんた今すぐ
イギリス帰れえー！
はっははは！
Stop stressing, Recruit.
大丈夫だってリクルート！
シスターには俺がちゃんとそういう時使う
魔法の言葉を教えてあるからな…
I've already taught Sister the magic words
to use if anything like that ever happens.
Magic?
魔法？
Oh yeah. No matter what they
say, my response should be:
あ～あ あれですか…
何を言われても…
"I don't understand Japanese."
ニホンゴ ワッカリマセーン
And that should get me out of most any trouble.
これで大抵のことは
なんとかなるのだそうだ
What is this, elementary school?!
あんたら小学生ですか？
He's right, though. Japanese people
are vulnerable to this phrase.
しかし 日本人は確かにこの言葉に弱い
Chapter 82: "No Worries"
わあ もうダメだ！
Ahh, this sucks! I'll be in all the
papers! All the evening shows!
ニュースだ ８時のニュースデビューだあ
はっはは リク！
Rec, you really are a good man.
やっぱりお前って いい奴だなあ
何言ってんすか？ やっぱりまだ事態を…
What are you saying?
Do you fully grasp the situation here?
Of course you don't want your dad
to find out you're here, right?
お前 ここにいることを
父親にバレたくねーのに
But your real concern is for
everyone else living down here.
さっきから人の心配ばっかりじゃねーか
Thanks for taking the time to come talk to us.
走って教えに来てくれて ありがとよ
Wha–?
ち 違いますよ 別に！
That's not it at all!
I live down here, so I have to look after my own—
俺は俺自身がここに住んでるから…
自分の為に…
Everything will be fine.
Your home is safe, and so is everyone else's.
大丈夫だよ
お前の家も俺達も…
You can't be sure of that.
そんな… なんの根拠もなく…
But still... why do I find
his words so comforting?
でも… それなのに
どうしてこいつの言葉は
こんなに心強いんだろうか…
I hate to admit it, but I actually
do feel a little better now.
悔しいことに なんか落ち着いてきた
Here, have a cookie.
まあ クッキーでも
No thank you.
いりません
Besides, I am sure this place is perfectly safe.
それにな
ここが大丈夫だっていう
根拠もあるんだぜ
You are?
そうなんですか？
Yup! You see, in case of such emergencies,
おうよ！ こんなことも あろうかと…
there's something special hidden down here.
俺は前からこの橋の下に…
I knew it! He's no ordinary man!
やっぱりこいつ ただ者じゃ…
I've created a Kappa Barrier to protect us.
妖術 河童結界を張っておいたのよ…
Underneath each corner of the bridge,
I buried cucumbers coated with bran.
橋の根元の四隅に
糠で包んだキュウリを埋めてな
Brilliant.
なるほど
Then I poured kappa extract over each spot!
そんでな その上から
河童のゆで汁を少々…
We're dead meat!
やっぱりもうダメだあ！
The only thing that will create is pickles.
漬物ができます…
Chapter 83: "City Official"
Father always takes the most direct
path to anything, no matter what.
父さんは どこに行くにも どんな時にも
迷わず最短ルートを選ぶ
And he doesn't take his time getting there.
そして そのスピードは とても速い
Just yesterday I learned about the plan
to develop the Arakawa riverside.
河川敷再開発のニュースを聞いたのは
昨日のこと…
Campaign to Create Riverside Parks
Mr. Tenryu Talks about Arakawa Project
Welcome to the New Society Homepage
Campaign to Create Riverside Parks
Mr. Tenryu Talks about Arakawa Project
Welcome to the New Society Homepage
Campaign to Create Riverside Parks
俺も自分なりに状況を
調べていたんだが…
Just a second!
はーい ちょっと待って
Sorry, I don't think I can make it to Mass today.
すいません…
今日はミサ出られそうにありません
I'm from the Ministry of Land.
国土交通省の者ですが…
この河川敷からの
立ち退きのお願いに来ました
His unnatural speed can only be truly
understood by his enemies.
その早さは 敵にしてみないと分からない
っていうか 君… ここまでやる人
見たことないよ ったくう…
Holy cow! I've never seen someone
go all-out like this before. Jeez...
Nice place.
いい部屋だなあ おい
Did you guys already finish the land survey?
地盤調査はもう終わったんですか？
ていうか 早過ぎません？
Wasn't that a little too fast?
When does construction begin?
いったい 工事はいつから？
Oh, here's the schedule.
あっ これ日程表
Well... construction doesn't start for a while,
but you should probably leave soon, anyway.
まあねえ 工事はまだ先だけど…
君 早く出てった方がいいよお
Even just being here is a crime.
大体これ 犯罪だからあ
警察の世話んなるのは嫌でしょ？
I'm sure you don't want the
police to get involved.
W—
We have another problem!
大変です～っ！
Some official came by with an eviction notice?
国交省のお役人が
立ち退きのお願いに来たあ？
あ… はい
Correct.
Huh? What's this mean?!
ええっ！ 何よこれ？
The hell's goin' on here?
はあーっ？ 聞いてねーぜ！
I thought we had more time.
昨日の今日で…
チッ 私としたことが油断した！
It seems I underestimated them.
I should've set up my incursion
countermeasures last night like I planned!
やはり昨晩のうちに侵入者防止トラップを
設置するべきだった…
What's the deal with all those sharp objects?
What kind of invasion are you worried about?
なんですか？ その超トゲトゲしたの？
なんの侵入を危惧してるんですか？
More importantly, why is this
happening all of a sudden?
でもよお なんで急に
こんなことになってんだよ？
お！ ああ… 実はこれ…
Oh, that's actually—
Damn those filthy Ministry officials!
国交省の役人共めえ！
シロさん？
Whitey?
Whitey's normally so calm and
gentle, and even he's angry.
あの温厚なシロさんが
こんな風に怒るなんて…
But what do you expect when you try
to kick someone out of their home?
そりゃそうだよな… 河川敷とはいえ
家から追い出されるんだもんな…
Still...
でも…
シロさん 違うんです
それ 国交省っていうか…
It's not the Ministry doing this,
Whitey. It's actually...
It's actually my father—
本当は俺の父さんが
そんなことは どうでもいいよお！
I don't care about any of that!
If they have time for this,
why can't they lay down more white lines?!
こんなことをしてる暇があったら
もっとたくさん白線を引けよお！
While they waste their time on this garbage,
こうしている間にも 道を失った俺みたいな
不幸な“渡ラー”が増えていくんだあ！
the number of underprivileged walkers
like me grows every day!
渡… 渡ラー？
Walkers?
"Haven't you played that game?"
やんなかったあ？
"The one where you have to stay
on the line until you get home?"
家に帰るまで
白線から出ちゃダメだっていうゲーム
Make
your
own
rules,
like
"if
you
step
off
the white
line,
girls
will
hate you"
If they can't accept responsibility,
え～ 責任が持てないなら…
ぐぅ～ 最初から白線なんて
引くんじゃない～！
they never should've drawn those
white lines in the first place!
Are you some kind of lost puppy?
捨て猫ですか？
I couldn't decide whether or not
to take Whitey's tears seriously.
シロさんの涙が重いんだか 軽いんだか
分かりませんでした…
Chapter 84: "Little Piggy"
ブヒィィィーー
Wh-Wh-Wh-What are we gonna do?!
どどど どど… どうしよう～？
おお… お兄ちゃん どうすればいいのう？
What do we do, Bro?
I-I-I don't know!
わわわ 分かんないよ～
Hey, Rec's the only one who's
actually met the official, right?
しかしまあ 役人さんと会ったのは
まだリクだけだな？
Yeah, everyone else should
have been here at Mass.
今朝のミサで みんなここに
集まってるはずだしなあ…
No.
いや…
There's one other person
who never comes to Mass.
１人だけ… 絶対ミサに
参加しない者がいる…
Excuse me! I'm from the Ministry of Land.
すみませーん 国交省の者ですけど！
Jeez, what's with this place?
How did this go unreported until now?
ったく… なんなんだ この河川敷…
よく今までニュースにもならずに…
なんなのよ もう…
What the hell?
ああん？
I thought that cross-dressing creep was the only
one with so much energy on a Sunday morning.
朝から元気なのは
どっかの女装癖だけにして欲しいわ…
Whoa, so hot!
うわっ 美人！
No, I mean... I'm here from
the Ministry of Land, and—
あっ いやその…
国土交通省の者なんですがあ…
Is that right? Well, how wonderful.
あらまぁ… 公務員さん？ 素敵ね
Yes, well... I'm here today to make a little request.
今日はちょっとお願いがあって…
Well, I wonder what it could be.
Out with it already,
まあ 何かしら… 言ってみなさいな
government swine.
公僕
Well, to be honest, I'm here
with an eviction notice for—
ええ 実は工事をするんで立ち退きを…
"Government swine"?
公僕？
うふふ… “お願い”するなら
Didn't your mother ever teach
you how to ask for a favor?
それ相応の姿勢があるでしょ？
Today's your lucky day. I'll teach you some
manners myself, you impudent maggot.
喜びなさい
無作法なウジ虫に
口のきき方を教えたげるわ
Hey, isn't that the guy?
なあ あれがお役人さんじゃね？
Ah, it is!
うわっ 本当だ！
ちょっ 皆さん大人しくしてて下さいよ！
Everyone just be quiet, okay?
He might get on your nerves,
結構横暴な奴で
カチンとくるかもしれませんが…
But he's from the government.
You don't wanna make this guy angry.
相手は国家権力…
怒らせたらどうなるか…
Um... hi there. I'm Mr. Suzuki,
from the Ministry of Land.
あの… わたくし
国土交通省の鈴木という…
I'm just a hideous swine feeding off
the generous teat of the public,
国民様に飼育して頂いている
醜い豚ですが…
but I'm here with a request.
国民様にお願いが…
Um... did you—
あの 君…
え？ すみません 躾のなってない豚で
本当にすみません
I'm sorry! I'm sorry for being such
a disrespectful little piggy!
Did you happen to see the woman
at the farm before coming here?
ここに来る前に
牧場のお姉さんに会った？
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
すみません！ すみません！
I'm sorry!
すみません！
Maria before noon is the embodiment of sadism.
I'm sorry! I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
寝起きのマリアは Sの化身だからな…
He'd already been thoroughly disciplined.
I'm sorry! I'm sorry!
調教済みでした…
Chapter 85: "Here"
He's like a different person.
別人だ…
Hey, bro.
おい 兄ちゃん
Are they really gonna start building here?
本当にここ 工事するのかい？
Yes. The contract hasn't actually
been finalized yet,
ええまあ…
実はまだ入札前ですが…
but it's all been decided. I'm sorry,
I had to come notify you. I'm sorry.
ほぼ決まりだろうということで
すみません
先に皆様にお知らせをと…
うっ すみませーん
ふーん…
Well, this little piggy had better
get going. I'm really sorry!
あの… じゃあ豚はこれで…
本当にすみませーん
What do we do, Chief?
We might really have to leave!
村長 どうします？
このままじゃ本当にここから
Would that be so bad? Life a little farther
down the road might be nice, too.
いいんじゃねーの？ 移動すりゃあ
水源の方の暮らしも 楽しそうじゃね？
そんな いい加減な！
How can you—
No!
いやだっ！
ニノさん？
Nino?
I wanna stay right here.
私はここにいたい！
I'm tired of getting thrown out
and isolated. I'm sick of it!
追い出されたり 離れ離れになるのは
もう嫌だ！
Chapter 86: "Arakawa Qwik-Skit Challenge"
Rock Star Challenge!
The Ad Lib Anthem!
I'll make up a song based
on any topic you give me!
あの日夕暮れ
And... okay, c'mon!
Barley tea.
Octopuses.
Magic.
Okay, baby! Open your ears and enjoy the show!
I always make sure to rent at least three DVDs.
愛のカケラ 探すたびに
I keep hoping that I get one good one,
but they all usually end up sucking.
いつも何故か 寂しくなる
Sorry
Refund
Oh crap, I just noticed that both discs of
"Planet Octotea 2: You Got Severed" are disc 2!
And the same with Wiztopus Rex!
Hit it! Everyone sing along!
もう行かなくちゃ
この空泣き出す前に
Don't touch it!
It'll eat your finger!
Says Nino, tossing a pill bug into the air.
There's a big bang in my mouth!
Says Nino, drinking a carbonated beverage.
サカサマになって
What a complicated equation.
君の事探して
Says Nino, staring at
a license plate.
Next time, on 11 BRIDGE!
いつまでも僕らは
As provided by Nino and the narrator.
Illustration: Kaworu Watashiya
たどり着けないまま
橋の下に立って
流れる渦に在って
いつまでも僕らは
その答え探して
yeah!
ロックスター 一発芸！ ザ・即興ソング
いただいたお題を使って
即興でソング作りまーす
お題
ヘイ カモン！
麦茶
タコ
魔法
オーケー ベイベー
聞いて下さーい 俺の歌～
タイトルは
「慎重な俺はDVDは
最低３本はレンタルする
１本でも当たりがあればと思ってたけど
全部はずれ
あれ？ よく見たら 麦茶の惑星って
両方共２巻じゃない？
あれ？ タコ伝説も…」
いくぞ～ 一緒に歌ってくれ～
ヘイッ ヘイッ ヘイッ
触ったらダメだ 指を巻き込まれるぞ！
そう言ってニノが投げたのは
ダンゴムシでした
口の中がビックバンだ
ニノが飲んだのは 炭酸飲料でした
難しい数式だなあ
車のナンバープレートでした
次回 「11 BRIDGE」
お相手はニノとナレーションでした